Guide to the Galvin family papers, 1906-1987.
Galvin family papers, 1906-1987
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Galvin family papers, 1906-1987.
4933
Galvin family
.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, passports, photographs, certificates, awards, biographical clippings, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, passports, photographs, certificates, awards, biographical clippings, and other papers of an upstate New York physician and college professor. Includes correspondence, accounts, historical descriptions, constitution and by-laws, and other papers pertaining to Cornell University's African-American fraternity, Alpha Phi Alpha.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Family members include Gregory Alexander Galvin, M.D., Meharry Medical College, and Corinne Brown Galvin, Ph.D., Ithaca College professor.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, passports, photographs, certificates, awards, biographical clippings, and other papers of an upstate New York physician and college professor. Includes correspondence, accounts, historical descriptions, constitution and by-laws, and other papers pertaining to Cornell University's African-American fraternity, Alpha Phi Alpha, including a paddle.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Galvin family.; Galvin, Corinne Brown, 1907-; Galvin, Gregory Alexander, 1907-; Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University--Societies, etc.; Ithaca College--Faculty.; Meharry Medical College.
Subjects:
African Americans--Students--Social life and customs--New York (State)--Ithaca.; African Americans--Education.; African Americans--Societies, etc.; Physicians (General practice)--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Family--New York (State)--Ithaca.
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.)--Social life and customs.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Galvin family papers
  - Passports and biographical clippings (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Medical Consultant, Department of Public Welfare, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - NYS Academy of General Practice (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Same, badges (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Certificates and Awards (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - First Baptist Church Documents (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - NYS Teachers Association, Equal Educational Opportunities Project, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Tompkins County Commission on Human Relations, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Jane McDougald Galvin-Lewis, Boston University (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Maharry Medical College, Alumni Directory, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Meharry Medical College, President's Award, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity papers
  - Correspondence, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Round-Up," 1955 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Alpha Chapter Accounts, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Convention Program, 1939, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Misc. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The History of Alpha Phi Alpha: A development in Negro College Life, 1935 edition and 1939 edition (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Senior Meritorious Service Award presented to G. Alex Galvin, M.D., 1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Charter for Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity, Alpha Chapter, Cornell University, 1906 (Box 3)
  - Family diplomas, certificates, and photographs, oversized (Box 3)
  - Alpha Phi Alpha paddle, signed by Galvin as President and fourteen others, May 25, 1940, 1022